https://www.candlemakers.co.uk/privacy-policy/

Navigation MenuHomeAbout UsShop OnlineCandlesWedding CandlesCandle Making SuppliesMouldsRigid/plastic
MouldsPolycarbonate MouldsFlexible/Rubber MouldsFloating Candle MouldsVacuum Formed Plastic MouldsGlass MouldsApplique Wax & CuttersCandle WaxesCandle WicksCandle DyesPerfumesEquipmentCandle Making KitsTextile & BatikSilk Painting and BatikDecorationHow to…Video Download InformationCandlemakers , Batik & Silk painting bookshelfCandle Making Safety InformationCandle Making ResourcesOur London ShopCandle Holders For HirePrivacy PolicyPrivacy PolicyPrivacy policyIntroduction1.1    We are committed to
safeguarding the privacy of www.candlemakers.co.uk visitors
and service users.1.2    This policy applies where we
are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of www.candlemakers.co.uk  visitors
and service users; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of
the processing of that personal data.1.3    We use cookies on our website.
Insofar as those cookies are not strictly necessary for the provision of www.candlemakers.co.uk  services,
we will ask you to consent to our use of cookies when you first visit our
website.1.4    Our website incorporates
privacy controls which affect how we will process your personal data. By using
the privacy controls, you can specify whether you would like to receive direct
marketing communications and limit the publication of your information. You can
access the privacy controls via www.candlemakers.co.uk 1.5    In this policy, “we”, “us” and
“our” refer to www.candlemakers.co.uk .
For more information about us, see Section 13.Credit2.1    This document was created
using a template from SEQ Legal (https://seqlegal.com).You must retain the above credit. Use of this
document without the credit is an infringement of copyright. However, you can
purchase from us an equivalent document that does not include the credit.How we use your
personal data3.1    In this Section 3 we have set
out:(a)    the general categories of
personal data that we may process;(b)    in the case of personal data
that we did not obtain directly from you, the source and specific categories of
that data;(c)    the purposes for which we may
process personal data; and(d)    the legal bases of the
processing.3.2    We may process data about your
use of our website and services (“usage data“). The usage data
may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version,
operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website
navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and
pattern of your service use. The source of the usage data is our analytics
tracking system. This usage data may be processed for the purposes of analysing
the use of the website and services. The legal basis for this processing is
consent3.3    We may process your account
data (“account
data“). The account data may include your name and email
address. The source of the account data is you or your employer. The account
data may be processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our
services, ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining
back-ups of our databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this
processing is consent.3.4    We may process your
information included in your personal profile on our website (“profile data“).
The profile data may include your name, address, telephone number, email
address, profile pictures, gender, date of birth, relationship status,
interests and hobbies, educational details and employment details. The profile
data may be processed for the purposes of enabling and monitoring your use of
our website and services. The legal basis for this processing is consent .3.5    We may process your personal
data that are provided in the course of the use of our services (“service data“).
The source of the service data is you or your employer. The service data may be
processed for the purposes of operating our website, providing our services,
ensuring the security of our website and services, maintaining back-ups of our
databases and communicating with you. The legal basis for this processing is
consent.3.6    We may process information
that you post for publication on our website or through our services (“publication data“).
The publication data may be processed [for the purposes of enabling such publication
and administering our website and services]. The legal basis for this
processing is consent.3.7    We may process information
contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding goods and/or services (“enquiry data“).
The enquiry data may be processed [for the purposes of offering, marketing and
selling relevant goods and/or services to you. The legal basis for this
processing is consent.3.8    We may process information
relating to our customer relationships, including customer contact information (“customer relationship
data“). The customer relationship data may include your name,
your employer, your job title or role, your contact details, and information
contained in communications between us and you or your employer. The source of
the customer relationship data is you or your employer. The customer
relationship data may be processed for the purposes of managing our
relationships with customers, communicating with customers, keeping records of
those communications and promoting our products and services to customers. The
legal basis for this processing is consent.3.9    We may process information
relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services that you
enter into with us and/or through our website (“transaction data”) .The
transaction data may include your contact details, your card details and the
transaction details. The transaction data may be processed for the purpose of
supplying the purchased goods and services and keeping proper records of those
transactions. The legal basis for this processing is the performance of a
contract between you and us and/or taking steps, at your request, to enter into
such a contract and our legitimate interests, namely the proper administration
of our website and business.3.10  We may process information that you
provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or
newsletters (“notification
data“). The notification data may be processed for the purposes
of sending you the relevant notifications and/or newsletters. The legal basis
for this processing is consent.3.11  We may process information contained
in or relating to any communication that you send to us (“correspondence data“).
The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata
associated with the communication. Our website will generate the metadata
associated with communications made using the website contact forms. The
correspondence data may be processed for the purposes of communicating with you
and record-keeping. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate
interests, namely the proper administration of our website and business and
communications with users.3.12  We may process any of your personal
data identified in this policy where necessary for the establishment, exercise
or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an
administrative or out-of-court procedure. The legal basis for this processing
is our legitimate interests, namely the protection and assertion of our legal
rights, your legal rights and the legal rights of others.3.13  We may process any of your personal
data identified in this policy where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or
maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional
advice. The legal basis for this processing is our legitimate interests, namely
the proper protection of our business against risks.3.14  In addition to the specific purposes
for which we may process your personal data set out in this Section 3, we may
also process any of your personal data where such processing is necessary for
compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to
protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.3.15  Please do not supply any other
person’s personal data to us, unless we prompt you to do so.Providing your
personal data to others4.1    We may disclose your personal
data to any member of our group of companies (this means our subsidiaries, our
ultimate holding company and all its subsidiaries) insofar as reasonably
necessary for the purposes, and on the legal bases, set out in this policy.4.2    We may disclose your personal
data to our insurers and/or professional advisers insofar as reasonably
necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage,
managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise
or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an
administrative or out-of-court procedure.4.3    Financial transactions
relating to our website and services are handled by our payment services
providers, PayPal. We will share transaction data with our payment services
providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your
payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries
relating to such payments and refunds. You can find information about the
payment services providers’ privacy policies and practices at www.PayPal.com.4.4    We may disclose your enquiry
data to one or more of those selected third party suppliers of goods and
services identified on our website for the purpose of enabling them to contact
you so that they can offer, market and sell to you relevant goods and/or
services. Each such third party will act as a data controller in relation to
the enquiry data that we supply to it; and upon contacting you, each such third
party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern
that third party’s use of your personal data.4.5    In addition to the specific
disclosures of personal data set out in this Section 4, we may disclose your
personal data where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal
obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests
or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your
personal data where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment,
exercise or defence of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an
administrative or out-of-court procedure.International
transfers of your personal data5.1    In this Section 5, we provide
information about the circumstances in which your personal data may be
transferred to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA).5.2    We and our other group
companies have offices and facilities in England. The European Commission has
made an “adequacy decision” with respect to the data protection laws of each of
these countries. Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by
appropriate safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses
adopted or approved by the European Commission.5.3    The hosting facilities for our
website are situated in France. The European Commission has made an “adequacy
decision” with respect to the data protection laws of each of these countries.
Transfers to each of these countries will be protected by appropriate
safeguards, namely the use of standard data protection clauses adopted or
approved by the European Commission.5.4    You acknowledge that personal
data that you submit for publication through our website or services may be
available, via the internet, around the world. We cannot prevent the use (or
misuse) of such personal data by others.Retaining and
deleting personal data6.1    This Section 6 sets out our
data retention policies and procedure, which are designed to help ensure that
we comply with our legal obligations in relation to the retention and deletion
of personal data.6.2    Personal data that we process
for any purpose or purposes shall not be kept for longer than is necessary for
that purpose or those purposes.6.3    We will retain your personal
data as follows:(a)    Personal data will be retained
for a minimum period of 1 years following 19/07/2018 and for a maximum period
of 5 years following 19/07/20186.4    In some cases it is not
possible for us to specify in advance the periods for which your personal data
will be retained. In such cases, we will determine the period of retention
based on the following criteria:6.5    Notwithstanding the other
provisions of this Section 6, we may retain your personal data where such
retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are
subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of
another natural person.Amendments7.1    We may update this policy from
time to time by publishing a new version on our website.7.2    You should check this page
occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes to this policy.7.3    We may OR notify you of
significant changes to this policy by email.Your rights8.1    In this Section 8, we have
summarised the rights that you have under data protection law. Some of the
rights are complex, and not all of the details have been included in our
summaries. Accordingly, you should read the relevant laws and guidance from the
regulatory authorities for a full explanation of these rights.8.2    Your principal rights under
data protection law are:(a)    the right to access;(b)    the right to rectification;(c)    the right to erasure;(d)    the right to restrict
processing;(e)    the right to object to
processing;(f)    the right to data portability;(g)    the right to complain to a
supervisory authority; and(h)    the right to withdraw consent.8.3    You have the right to
confirmation as to whether or not we process your personal data and, where we
do, access to the personal data, together with certain additional information.
That additional information includes details of the purposes of the processing,
the categories of personal data concerned and the recipients of the personal
data. Providing the rights and freedoms of others are not affected, we will
supply to you a copy of your personal data. The first copy will be provided
free of charge, but additional copies may be subject to a reasonable fee. You
can access your personal data by visiting https://suppliesforcandles.co.uk8.4    You have the right to have any
inaccurate personal data about you rectified and, taking into account the
purposes of the processing, to have any incomplete personal data about you
completed.8.5    In some circumstances you have
the right to the erasure of your personal data without undue delay. Those
circumstances include: the personal data are no longer necessary in relation to
the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed; you withdraw
consent to consent-based processing; you object to the processing under certain
rules of applicable data protection law; the processing is for direct marketing
purposes; and the personal data have been unlawfully processed. However, there
are exclusions of the right to erasure. The general exclusions include where
processing is necessary: for exercising the right of freedom of expression and
information; for compliance with a legal obligation; or for the establishment,
exercise or defence of legal claims.8.6    In some circumstances you have
the right to restrict the processing of your personal data. Those circumstances
are: you contest the accuracy of the personal data; processing is unlawful but
you oppose erasure; we no longer need the personal data for the purposes of our
processing, but you require personal data for the establishment, exercise or
defence of legal claims; and you have objected to processing, pending the
verification of that objection. Where processing has been restricted on this
basis, we may continue to store your personal data. However, we will only
otherwise process it: with your consent; for the establishment, exercise or
defence of legal claims; for the protection of the rights of another natural or
legal person; or for reasons of important public interest.8.7    You have the right to object
to our processing of your personal data on grounds relating to your particular
situation, but only to the extent that the legal basis for the processing is
that the processing is necessary for: the performance of a task carried out in
the public interest or in the exercise of any official authority vested in us;
or the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by us or by a third party.
If you make such an objection, we will cease to process the personal
information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the
processing which override your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing
is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.8.8    You have the right to object
to our processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes
(including profiling for direct marketing purposes). If you make such an
objection, we will cease to process your personal data for this purpose.8.9    You have the right to object
to our processing of your personal data for scientific or historical research
purposes or statistical purposes on grounds relating to your particular situation,
unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out
for reasons of public interest.8.10  To the extent that the legal basis
for our processing of your personal data is:(a)    consent; or(b)    that the processing is necessary
for the performance of a contract to which you are party or in order to take
steps at your request prior to entering into a contract,and such processing is carried out by automated
means, you have the right to receive your personal data from us in a structured,
commonly used and machine-readable format. However, this right does not apply
where it would adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.8.11  If you consider that our processing
of your personal information infringes data protection laws, you have a legal
right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority responsible for data
protection. You may do so in the EU member state of your habitual residence,
your place of work or the place of the alleged infringement.8.12  To the extent that the legal basis
for our processing of your personal information is consent, you have the right
to withdraw that consent at any time. Withdrawal will not affect the lawfulness
of processing before the withdrawal.8.13  You may exercise any of your rights
in relation to your personal data by written notice to us OR by email, in
addition to the other methods specified in this Section 8.About cookies9.1    A cookie is a file containing
an identifier (a string of letters and numbers) that is sent by a web server to
a web browser and is stored by the browser. The identifier is then sent back to
the server each time the browser requests a page from the server.9.2    Cookies may be either
“persistent” cookies or “session” cookies: a persistent cookie will be stored
by a web browser and will remain valid until its set expiry date, unless
deleted by the user before the expiry date; a session cookie, on the other
hand, will expire at the end of the user session, when the web browser is
closed.9.3    Cookies do not typically
contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal
information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in
and obtained from cookies.Cookies that we
use10.1  We use cookies for the following
purposes:(a)    authentication – we use
cookies to identify you when you visit our website and as you navigate our
website(b)    Status – we use cookies to
help us to determine if you are logged into our website(c)    Personalization – we use
cookies [to store information about your preferences and to personalise the
website for you(d)    Security – we use cookies as
an element of the security measures used to protect user accounts, including
preventing fraudulent use of login credentials, and to protect our website and
services generally.(e)    Advertising – we use cookies
[to help us to display advertisements that will be relevant to you.(f)    Analysis – we use cookies [to
help us to analyse the use and performance of our website and services.(g)    Cookie consent – we use
cookies to store your preferences in relation to the use of cookies more
generally.Cookies used by
our service providers11.1  Our service providers use cookies
and those cookies may be stored on your computer when you visit our website.11.2  We use Google Analytics to analyse
the use of our website. Google Analytics gathers information about website use
by means of cookies. The information gathered relating to our website is used
to create reports about the use of our website. Google’s privacy policy is
available at: https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/.Managing cookies12.1  Most browsers allow you to refuse to
accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from
browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain
up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:(a)    https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en (Chrome);(b)    https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences (Firefox);(c)    http://www.opera.com/help/tutorials/security/cookies/ (Opera);(d)    https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies (Internet
Explorer);(e)    https://support.apple.com/kb/PH21411 (Safari);
and(f)    https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/windows-10-microsoft-edge-and-privacy (Edge).12.2  Blocking all cookies will have a
negative impact upon the usability of many websites.12.3  If you block cookies, you will not
be able to use all the features on our website.Our details13.4  You can contact us:(a)    by post, to the postal address
published on our website; (b)
by telephone, on the contact number published on our website;(c)    by email, using the email
address published on our website.ffffffffffSearch productsBest SellersOur Candle CreationsApplique WaxCandle Making KitsCandle WicksCandle DyesPerfumesOrderingGet In TouchE-mail:
mail@candlemakers.co.uk
Mail Order Tel: 0207 602 4031Candlemakers Supplies
Behind 102, Shepherds Bush Rd
Entrance in Batoum Gardens
London. W6 7PD
Tel: 0207 6021812Opening Hours:
Our London shop is closed on Mondays, until further notice.Tue-Fri 10.30 am- 6pm.
Sat 10.30 am – 5.00 pmThe Candle Workshop
Gelligroes Mill
Blackwood, Gwent
NP12 2HY
Tel: 01495 222322Opening Hours
Mon-Fri
9:30am -5:30pm
Sat
10:30am -5:30pm
Social LinksFacebook
Email: mail@candlemakers.co.uk
Call Us: 01495 222322More OptionsBespoke CandlesBookshelfCandlemaking ClassesWedding CandlesHandy Candle Making ResourcesTutorialsSpring Chick Candle TutorialSwirly Stars Candle TutorialXmas Applique TutorialSnow Spiral Candle TutorialGlitter Star Candle TutorialBeeswax Sheet TutorialSnowball Candle TutorialBest SellersOur Candle CreationsApplique WaxCandle Making KitsCandle WicksCandle DyesPerfumesOrderingYour Shopping BagPrivacy Policy2018 Copyright of Candle Makers, BlackwoodThis website uses cookies to provide you with the best browsing experience.Find out more or adjust your settings.
Accept
Privacy Overview
Strictly Necessary Cookies
Powered by GDPR plugin
Privacy OverviewThis website uses cookies so that we can provide you with the best user experience possible. Cookie information is stored in your browser and performs functions such as recognising you when you return to our website and helping our team to understand which sections of the website you find most interesting and useful.
Strictly Necessary CookiesStrictly Necessary Cookie should be enabled at all times so that we can save your preferences for cookie settings.
disable
If you disable this cookie, we will not be able to save your preferences. This means that every time you visit this website you will need to enable or disable cookies again.
Enable All
Save Settings
